<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pupillomtry | Friederike Schütte</title>
    <link>https://friederikeschuette.netlify.app/tag/pupillomtry/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://friederikeschuette.netlify.app/tag/pupillomtry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>pupillomtry</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://friederikeschuette.netlify.app/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>pupillomtry</title>
      <link>https://friederikeschuette.netlify.app/tag/pupillomtry/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The P600, P3, and phasic noradrenaline release</title>
      <link>https://friederikeschuette.netlify.app/project/internal-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://friederikeschuette.netlify.app/project/internal-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The P600 component of the event-related potential (ERP) is typically observed upon grammaticality violations, reversal anomalies, and syntactic ambiguities when
reading or listening to sentences. It is often interpreted as a signal of specific linguistic syntactic and combinatorial operations and continues to inform
neurocognitive models of language comprehension. However, its underlying process is still not agreed upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PhD project aims to contribute to the current debate about how much the cognitive process underlying the P600 is tied to cognitive control and whether it
might be a variant of a more domain-general component (the P3) and thus not reflect a specific linguistic process per se. More specifically, my project
further tests the hypothesis that – possibly just like the P3 – the P600 might reflect phasic norepinephrine release from the locus coeruleus (LC-NE) to
motivationally significant stimuli more generally (Sassenhagen et al., 2014; Sassenhagen &amp;amp; Bornkessel-Schlesewsky, 2015; Sassenhagen &amp;amp; Fiebach, 2019).
To this end, I link EEG activity recorded during sentence processing tasks to reaction time and pupillary measures. In addition, we plan to manipulate
noradrenaline release non-invasively via transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation. My advisers are Milena Rabovsky, Mathias Weymar, and Isabell Wartenburger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To hear more about our studies and first results, visit our talks at the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMLaP 2021 (September 4, 2.15-3.15 pm CEST)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SNL 2021 (October 7, 3-5 pm CEST)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
